
--- https://fez-delivery-co.gitbook.io/fezcorporate-api-docs/api-endpoints/orders/fetch-delivery-cost ---
For the complete documentation index, see llms.txt . This page is also available as Markdown . Copy On this page API ENDPOINTS Orders Fetch Delivery Cost This is the endpoint for fetching the cost of delivery .It takes a non mandatory parameter - state. If state is not passed, the cost of delivery to all the states and FCT is returned. By default, the cost returned when state field is not passed is based on the weight of the parcel being between 0-5kg. To get the cost of the delivery based on the weight of the parcel, please add the weight field. Please note that the delivery cost API assumes pick up location (state) is the state configured in your organization's profile and the cost returned is between a pick up location in that state to any state you pass in the request. For example, if your business is configured to be operating out of Rivers State, the cost returned from this endpoint will be from Rivers State to any state passed in the request as the destination state or from Rivers to all the 36 States and FCT,if the state field is empty. Delivery Cost Endpoint => /order/cost POST /order/cost Kindly use cost (lowercase) instead of Cost in the response body. Please note that the actual amount charged is the sum of VAT and cost , which represents the total cost . Headers Name Type Description Authorization * String Your Bearer Token secret-key * String Your Secret Key Request Body Name Type Description state String The Destination State to deliver to pickUpState String The State from which the Item is leaving (Optional) weight Numeric Weight of order (Optional) locker Boolean Indicate that the delivery should via locker. (Default: false) 200 Success 401 Unauthorized Copy { " status " : " Success " , " description " : " Cost Fetched Successfully " , " Cost " : { " state " : " Kano " , " cost " : 6000 }, " cost " : { " state " : " Kano " , " cost " : 6000 }, " vat " : { " vatAmount " : 450 , " vatPercent " : " 7.50 " }, " totalCost " : 6450 } Copy { "status": "Error", "description": "Organization Secret Key is Required" } Previous Status With Date Range Next Track Last updated 2 months ago

--- https://fez-delivery-co.gitbook.io/fezcorporate-api-docs/api-endpoints/orders/create ---
For the complete documentation index, see llms.txt . This page is also available as Markdown . Copy On this page API ENDPOINTS Orders Create This is the endpoint for creating an order or requesting a pick up. This endpoint can be used for single or multiple request. It takes an array object(s). Create Order Endpoint => /order POST /order Headers Name Type Description Authorization * String Your Bearer Token secret-key * String Your Secret Key Request Body Name Type Description recipientAddress * String Recipient Address (Delivery destination) recipientState * String Must be any of the 36 states or FCT recipientName * String Recipient Name recipientPhone * String Recipient Phone or Mobile number recipientEmail Email Recipient Email uniqueID * String Any value that uniquely identifies a delivery request from the client's side BatchID * String Any value that identifies the request. i.e all the delivery requests in an API call should have the same Batch ID. CustToken String if your organization sends a token to recipient for confirmation of receipt purpose, please include the token here. itemDescription String Description of the order additionalDetails String Any additional details you want us to know about the order. You can add additional recipient phone numbers or address landmark here. valueOfItem * String The value of items weight * Integer Weight of item in Kg (Kilogram) pickUpState string Must be any of the 36 states or FCT (optional) pickUpAddress string The address from which the item to be sent should be picked up from. Its Optional. If not supplied, the business address is used. waybillNumber string Unique string from 3rd party logistics partners for a given order. pickUpDate Date Date in which you want the order to be picked up (Optional) isItemCod Boolean A boolean flag indicating if the item delivered is to be paid for at the point of delivery. its optional and its default value is false.(Optional) cashOnDeliveryAmount Decimal | Integer Amount to be paid for the Item been delivered. (Optional) fragile Boolean An indicator that the item to be delivered is fragile. (Default : false) lockerID string The selected locker ID to deliver the item to. (Optional) recipientAlternatePhone string Recipient Alternate Phone or Mobile number (Optional) 201: Created Success 401 Unauthorized Good to know: By default, the name, address and phone number of your organization as set during the onboarding process is captured as the sender's name, sender's address, sender's phone number respectively. However, if you want to specify a different senders Name, senders Address and phone number, please add the following field in the request parameter thirdparty: Please set to "true" i.e "thirdparty": "true". senderName: The name of the sender. senderAddress: The address of the sender. senderPhone: The phone number of the sender. Upon successfully creating the order, the API returns an array object that consist of the orderNo for each request. Previous Orders Next Get Last updated 5 months ago

--- https://fez-delivery-co.gitbook.io/fezcorporate-api-docs/api-endpoints/orders/track ---
For the complete documentation index, see llms.txt . This page is also available as Markdown . Copy On this page API ENDPOINTS Orders Track This is the endpoint can be used to get the status of an order and view the delivery timeline of that order. This endpoints returns an order object which includes the status of the order, sender/recipient name and sender/recipient address. It also returns the history object which contains the history/timeline of the order. Endpoint => /order/track/{orderNumber} GET /order/track/{orderNumber} Headers Name Type Description Authorization * String Your Bearer Token secret-key * String Your Secret Key 200 Success 401 Unauthorized Copy { " status " : " Success " , " description " : " History Fetched " , " order " : { " orderNo " : " 1T7002122309 " , " orderStatus " : " Dispatched " , " recipientAddress " : " 10 " , " recipientName " : " ferferf " , " senderAddress " : " 3A SULAIMON SHODERU STREET, HARUNA BUS STOP, IKORODU " , " senderName " : " KIDS PLACE " , " recipientState " : " Lagos " , " createdAt " : " 2023-12-02 06:14:09 " , " timezone " : " Africa/Lagos " , " proofOfDelivery " : null }, " history " : [ { " orderStatus " : " Dispatched " , " statusCreationDate " : " 2023-12-02 13:14:40 " , " statusDescription " : " Your package is on its way to the delivery address and is en route to the customer " }, { " orderStatus " : " Picked-Up " , " statusCreationDate " : " 2023-12-02 13:14:09 " , " statusDescription " : " Our rider has picked-up your item and is heading back to the office " } ] } Previous Fetch Delivery Cost Next Delivery Time Estimate Last updated 2 months ago

--- https://fez-delivery-co.gitbook.io/fezcorporate-api-docs/api-endpoints/webhook/order-webhook-request ---
For the complete documentation index, see llms.txt . This page is also available as Markdown . Copy On this page API ENDPOINTS Webhook Order Webhook Request This endpoint is defined by the client, typically specified as a callback URL during webhook registration. It is invoked whenever an order changes its state (status). This endpoint Delivers an order status change notification to the client's registered webhook endpoint. By the time execution reaches here, the system has already confirmed that the associated order exists, that the client has a registered webhook endpoint, and that the retry limit has not been exhausted. The target URL is the client's own server ù it may be any external system the client has configured to receive real-time order updates (e.g. their own backend, a third-party logistics platform, or an ERP). The payload is intentionally minimal: only the order reference and the new status are sent, keeping the contract stable and avoiding exposure of sensitive order internals. Each request is signed using a shared secret (the client's API secret key) so the receiving server can independently verify that the notification genuinely originated from this platform and has not been tampered with in transit. Note that the registered url is a POST route. Json body will be sent to this route and will contain orderNumber and s tatus as request body. Request POST /{{userDefinedBaseUrl}} Request Headers Name Type Description Content-Type String application/json X-Caller-Domain String The base URL of this platform (identifies the sender). X-Timestamp String Unix timestamp of when the request was signed (used for replay-attack prevention). X-Signature String HMAC-SHA256 hex digest of (orderNo + orderStatus + timestamp) signed with the client's secret key. The receiver should recompute this and reject requests where the signature does not match. Request Body Name Type Description orderNumber * String Your order unique ID on fez status * String The new status of your order 200 Success 401 Unauthorized 422 Validation Error Previous Register Order Webhook Last updated 3 months ago

--- https://fez-delivery-co.gitbook.io/fezcorporate-api-docs/api-endpoints/orders/states ---
For the complete documentation index, see llms.txt . This page is also available as Markdown . Copy On this page API ENDPOINTS Orders States This is the endpoint for provides a list of all states in nigeria. Delivery Time Estimate Endpoint => /states GET / states Headers Name Type Description Authorization * String Your Bearer Token secret-key * String Your Secret Key 201: Created Success 401 Unauthorized Copy { " status " : " Success " , " description " : " states fetched successfully " , " states " : [ { " id " : 1 , " state " : " Kano " }, { " id " : 2 , " state " : " Lagos " }, { " id " : 3 , " state " : " Kaduna " }, { " id " : 4 , " state " : " Katsina " }, { " id " : 5 , " state " : " Oyo " }, { " id " : 6 , " state " : " Rivers " }, { " id " : 7 , " state " : " Bauchi " }, { " id " : 8 , " state " : " Jigawa " }, { " id " : 9 , " state " : " Benue " }, { " id " : 10 , " state " : " Anambra " }, { " id " : 11 , " state " : " Borno " }, { " id " : 12 , " state " : " Delta " }, { " id " : 13 , " state " : " Imo " }, { " id " : 14 , " state " : " Niger " }, { " id " : 15 , " state " : " Akwa Ibom " }, { " id " : 16 , " state " : " Ogun " }, { " id " : 17 , " state " : " Sokoto " }, { " id " : 18 , " state " : " Ondo " }, { " id " : 19 , " state " : " Osun " }, { " id " : 20 , " state " : " Kogi " }, { " id " : 21 , " state " : " Zamfara " }, { " id " : 22 , " state " : " Enugu " }, { " id " : 23 , " state " : " Kebbi " }, { " id " : 24 , " state " : " Edo " }, { " id " : 25 , " state " : " Plateau " }, { " id " : 26 , " state " : " Adamawa " }, { " id " : 27 , " state " : " Cross River " }, { " id " : 28 , " state " : " Abia " }, { " id " : 29 , " state " : " Ekiti " }, { " id " : 30 , " state " : " Kwara " }, { " id " : 31 , " state " : " Gombe " }, { " id " : 32 , " state " : " Yobe " }, { " id " : 33 , " state " : " Taraba " }, { " id " : 34 , " state " : " Ebonyi " }, { " id " : 35 , " state " : " Nasarawa " }, { " id " : 36 , " state " : " Bayelsa " }, { " id " : 37 , " state " : " FCT " } ] } Previous Pickup Hubs Next International Orders Last updated 8 months ago
